Welcome to this course on Ajax.
مرحبًا بكم في هذا الدرس عن Ajax.
The main concept of Ajax is simple.
المفهوم الاساسي لـ Ajax بسيط.
You make a request for some data,
تقوم بطلب بعض البيانات،
and then without pausing for everything to wait for the request of return,
وبدون توقف لأي شخص لانتظار طلب العودة،
You just move on and do something else.
تُكمل لعمل شيء آخر.
Then once the requests finally does get returned you deal with it.
ثم بعد أن تعود الطلبات أخيرًا تتعامل معها.
Really, that's Ajax in a nutshell.
هذا هو حقًا Ajax باختصار.
Now Ajax used to be an acronym for Asynchronous JavaScript And XML,
كانت كلمة Ajax اختصارًا لـAsynchronous JavaScript And XML،
and you'll still kind of see it that way,
وستظل تراها هكذا،
but it's a bit of a misnomer now.
ولكنه وصف خاطئ إلى حد ما الآن.
Instead Ajax is the concept of asynchronously requesting data,
بدلاً من أن Ajax هي طلب البيانات غير المتزامن،
whether that's an XML file,
سواء كان ملف XML
a JavaScript file, or Json from a REST API.
أو ملف JavaScript أو Json من REST API.
It really doesn't matter what the data is.
لا يهم حقًا ما هو نوع البيانات.
You just request the data asynchronously and then deal with it when it comes back.
أنت تطلب البيانات بشكل غير متزامن ثم تتعامل معها عندما تأتي.
In this course, you'll learn to make Ajax requests using JavaScript.
ستتعلم في هذا الدرس كيفية عمل طلبات Ajax باستخدام JavaScript.
First, we'll look at doing this with the tried-and-true XHR object.
أولاً، سنرى القيام بذلك بواسطة عنصر XHR حقيقي ومُجرب.
Then we'll look at how jQuery makes Ajax requests in lesson two.
ثم سنرى كيف تقوم jQuery بطلبات Ajax في الدرس الثاني.
And finally, in lesson three,
وأخيرًا، في الدرس الثالث،
we'll check out the new and massively improved way of making
سنرى الطريقة الجديدة والمُطورة بشكل هائل للقيام
async requests using the fetch API. You're gonna love it.
بطلبات غير متزامنة باستخدام API الإحضار. ستحبون ذلك.
So my mom's birthday is coming up soon and I need to make a cake for her.
لقد اقترب عيد ميلاد والدتي وسأذهب لصنع الكيك لها.
So while I go to the store to get the ingredients,
لذا، أثناء ذهابي للمتجر لإحضار مكونات الكيك،
some of my friends are going to help demo how
سيقوم بعض أصدقائي بعمل عرض توضيحي عن كيفية
Ajax communication works when interacting with a server.
عمل اتصالات Ajax عندما تتفاعل مع الخادم.